SHREY GUPTA

January 28, 2018

Computer Engineer



17, West Avenue Road Punjabi Bagh New Delhi — 110026 India

+91 - 9717799361 shrey.gupta1904@gmail.com http://www.shreygupta.net

ABOUT ME

Upcoming computer engineer possessing strong teamwork and organizational skills through hands-on experience and working in various team projects. I am a person who is keen to find logic behind everything and my whimsical jokes keep the environment lively. I have been programming for a couple now but have also dipped my toes in various other technologies – Robotics, Mobile App Development & Machine Learning, just to name a few.

EDUCATION

Maharaja Agrasen Institute of Technology, New Delhi

Bachelor of Technology (B. Tech), Computer Science

2015 - Present CGPA: 8.59/10

Springdales School, Pusa Road, New Delhi

XII (Senior Secondary), Science

May 2015

Aggregate: 90.80%

Springdales School, Pusa Road, New Delhi

X (Secondary)

May 2013 CGPA: 10.00/10

EXPERIENCE

Event Organizer | Techsurge (MAIT's Technical Fest)

06/04/2017 - 08/04/2017

Techsurge & Mridang 2K17 is the Annual Technical and Cultural Fest of Maharaja Agrasen Institute of Technology. Being in the Core Team, I helped the student body in organizing and managing different events throughout the fest.

Trainee | APTRON Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

01/06/2017 - 15/07/2017

While learning Android at Aptron Solutions Pvt. Ltd, I got a chance to work on an Android Application. We developed a Hospital Management System, which I further converged to an exclusive Doctor-Patient Management Application to make it as user friendly as possible for the users.

TRAININGS

Machine Learning Foundation Nanodegree

Udacity (co-created By Kaggle) (Online) | January 2018 - April 2018

Machine Learning, being a very hot buzzword in the industry today, provides the ability to make the computers act without explicitly programming them. I am currently pursuing this course, learning new concepts and applications of the same every day. There are fascinating use cases and real-world problems making the learning interesting. Many projects included in the course are being worked upon.

The Web Developer Bootcamp

Udemy (Online) | September 2017 - Present

Browsing through different advanced websites on the interweb always made me curious about what runs them. This course provided me with a complete package including HTML, CSS, JavaScript and various other frameworks such as MongoDB, NodeJS, AngularJS, BootStrap etc. that are currently used in Front-end and Back-end web development.

Android Basics Nanodegree by Google

Udacity (co-created By Google) (Online) | July 2017 - September 2017

One of the best courses provided by Google to brush up Android Application Development Skills. From making an empty activity to applying material design, this course has it all. I made about various Android Applications during this course. (Quiz App, Basketball Score Keeper App, Tour Guide App, Inventory App etc.)

Android Application Development

APTRON Solutions Pvt. Ltd. | June 2017 - July 2017

Android, a mobile operating system developed by Google, runs on more than 2 billion devices around the globe. This course helped me understand the basics and the working of the operating system itself and then I developed different applications for practical scenarios during the same. It was fun to work with XML, Java in the official IDE – Android Studio.

Python for Everybody Specialization

Coursera (by University of Michigan) (Online) | June 2016

Python is a very powerful high-level programming language. As I came to know about the various different fields where python is used, I got interested to learn it. I joined this five — course specialization that got me through python 2.7 covering data structures, flow of control, accessing web data etc.

SKILLS & COMPETENCES

- Leadership
- Teamwork and collaboration
- Innovative & Critical Thinker

Languages

- Python (2.7 & 3.6)
- C/C++
- Java
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript

Tools

- Anaconda
- Android
- Linux

Technologies

- Machine Learning
- Artificial Intelligence
- Raspberry Pi
- Android
- MongoDB / SQL

Hobbies & Interests

- Listening Music
- Gaming
- Watching TV Shows

PROJECTS

DoctorOnTheGo

Android Application | August 2017 - November 2017

This is a Doctor Patient Appointment Management Application, which intends to bridge the gap between patients & doctors. The application provides the functionality of letting patients book appointments with doctors and helping doctors to manage those patients' medications & prescriptions, according to the timeline of the treatment.

Home Automation

Raspberry Pi (IOT) | August 2016 – October 2016

Putting together a few wires and parts such as Raspberry Pi, Relay, I made a Home Automation system that can be controlled using a web interface or an Android App. Different Home Appliances or Electronic/Electrical devices running on 220 volts AC having wattage upto 2000 Watts were automated using the system.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Principle's Special Award | November 2014
 Got the Principle's Special Award for outstanding contribution in Computers.
- School Prefect Springdales School | Batch 2014 2015
 Represented the student body and the school in various interschool events.